<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Diffmerge | SushiHangover]]></title>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/blog/categories/diffmerge/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-03T13:15:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[RobertN]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Os X : Using Diff Merge As Your Git Visual Merge And Diff Tool]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/using-diffmerge-as-your-git-visual-merge-and-diff-tool/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T20:56:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/using-diffmerge-as-your-git-visual-merge-and-diff-tool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/diffmerge_large.png">{% img right /images/diffmerge_small.png &ldquo;LLVM vs. GCC code generation for Bare Metal ARM development&rdquo; %}</a>
I tend to stay on the cmd line as much as possible, but for visual diffs, an ncurses console diff tool just does not cut it for me. <a href="http://www.scootersoftware.com/moreinfo.php">Beyond Compare Pro</a> by <a href="http://www.scootersoftware.com/index.php">Scooter</a> on Windows is one of best that I have ever used and with licenses at work I never had to worry about not having it on a work desktop or laptop.</p>

<p>But on OS-X at home, Beyond Compare was not available. There is a 4.0 release in the works (beta now), but $50.00 USD for a personal-use copy on OS-X and not having feature parity with Windows Pro features(?), I just can not pull the trigger on that purchuse when there are other
(cheaper) options that work just as well for personal development.</p>

<p>So, normally for a <strong>free</strong> visual diff, you can not beat <a href="http://meldmerge.org">meld</a>, it is a great open-source tool, but on OS-X it fires up X (Quartz for me) and it getting long in the tooth in terms of the GUI&rsquo;s human factors (feature set is still great). If there was a Qt version of this, the search would be over&hellip; free or not!</p>

<p>So some searching landed me on an old post by <a href="http://twobitlabs.com/2011/08/install-diffmerge-git-mac-os-x/">Todd Huss</a> about using DiffMerge as your visual diff/merge for git and it was actually what I was looking for, well almost ;-) It is missing a few features, but they have a free version and it works really well and has a great OS-X interface&hellip; search is over for now&hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.sourcegear.com/diffmerge/">SourceGear</a> has a $19.00 USD version that include file export with HTML formatting and if I could see example HTML code that it produces, I pay for that feature in a heart-beat, but the feature is completely locked out till you actaully register, bummer&hellip;</p></blockquote>

<p>Todd recommends using the DiffMerge installer version vs. the dmg version, I go the other way on that. Download the dmg version, open it and drag/drop the app to your Applications. Then in a term window you can copy the <em>Extras/diffmerge.sh</em> to your <em>/usr/local/bin</em> directory (Execute attrib is already set, so no chmod needed..), but I copied it as just <em>vdiff</em> as that is quicker to type. No admin rights are need to install it that way and that makes me happy&hellip; I can <em>vdiff file1.c file2.c</em> on the cmd line to pop the GUI open and populate it.</p>

<p>I then used the git setup he has listed and everything is working great so far. Click on the image above to it comparing the disassembly of <a href="/images/diffmerge_large.png">LLVM vs. GCC code generation for bare metal ARM</a> development.</p>

<p>{% codeblock lang:bash Your git setup is: %}
git config &ndash;global diff.tool diffmerge
git config &ndash;global difftool.diffmerge.cmd &lsquo;diffmerge &ldquo;$LOCAL&rdquo; &ldquo;$REMOTE&rdquo;&rsquo;
git config &ndash;global merge.tool diffmerge
git config &ndash;global mergetool.diffmerge.cmd &lsquo;diffmerge &ndash;merge &ndash;result=&ldquo;$MERGED&rdquo; &ldquo;$LOCAL&rdquo; &ldquo;$(if test -f &rdquo;$BASE"; then echo &ldquo;$BASE&rdquo;; else echo &ldquo;$LOCAL&rdquo;; fi)&ldquo; &rdquo;$REMOTE"&rsquo;
git config &ndash;global mergetool.diffmerge.trustExitCode true
{% endcodeblock %}</p>

<p>{% codeblock lang:bash Your git shortcuts are: linenos:false %}</p>

<h1>diff the local file.m against the checked-in version</h1>

<p>git difftool file.m</p>

<h1>diff the local file.m against the version in some-feature-branch</h1>

<p>git difftool some-feature-branch file.m</p>

<h1>diff the file.m from the Build-54 tag to the Build-55 tag</h1>

<p>git difftool Build-54..Build-55 file.m</p>

<h1>To resolve merge conflicts, just run git mergetool:</h1>

<p>git mergetool
{% endcodeblock %}</p>

<p>Thanks <a href="http://twobitlabs.com">Todd</a>, works great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
