<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ARM | SushiHangover]]></title>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/blog/categories/arm/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-19T02:09:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Robert N.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qemu 2.0.0 Is Released (or Maybe 1.7.9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/qemu-2-dot-0-0-is-released-as-1-dot-7-9"/>
    <updated>2014-04-17T23:20:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/qemu-2-dot-0-0-is-released-as-1-dot-7-9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://wiki.qemu.org/Main_Page"><img class="left" src="/images/QEMU_logo.png" title="&ldquo;QEMU&rdquo;" ></a> QEMU 2.0.0 is now <a href="http://lists.nongnu.org/archive/html/qemu-devel/2014-04/msg02734.html">released</a>.</p>

<p>The full list of changes are available at: <a href="http://wiki.qemu.org/ChangeLog/2.0">http://wiki.qemu.org/ChangeLog/2.0</a></p>

<p>It appears that doing a checkout of tag &lsquo;v2.0.0&rsquo;, build and install will produce a binary that reports version 1.7.9</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>git status
</span><span class='line'>HEAD detached at v2.0.0
</span><span class='line'>nothing to commit, working directory clean
</span><span class='line'>qemu-system-arm &mdash;version
</span><span class='line'>QEMU emulator version 1.7.93, Copyright &copy; 2003-2008 Fabrice Bellard</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>I did a quick look and they are pulling the version during the ./configure stage so since I am always on the master (bleed-edge) branch, my installed version shows up as 1.7.9. You will need to checkout, <strong>configure</strong>, build and install to produce a binary that has the correct version (<del>QEMUVERSION</del>) assigned:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>qemu-system-arm &mdash;version
</span><span class='line'>QEMU emulator version 2.0.0, Copyright &copy; 2003-2008 Fabrice Bellard</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[$30 60MSPS Logic Analyzer - Logic Pirate]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/0-60msps-logic-analyzer"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T20:16:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/0-60msps-logic-analyzer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://http://dangerousprototypes.com"><img class="left" src="/images/dangerous_logo.png" title="&ldquo;Dangerous Prototypes&rdquo;" ></a> I do not do a lot of product promotions, but this Logic Analyser from Dangerous Prototypes is so sweet! It is such a simple hardware design, pulled together with some great programming and serial ram overclocking. For $30USD you get an 8 channel, 256k sample, 60 Mhz(!!! &ndash; overclocked) logic analyser that supports the SUMP logic analyzer protocol and thus can use the Logic Sniffer (An alternative OLS client), another great open source product.</p>

<p>This item is on my list now for future debugging of my bare-metal ARM designs.</p>

<p>So check it out yourself:</p>

<p>DP Blog post: <a href="http://dangerousprototypes.com/2014/04/15/new-prototype-logic-pirate-8-channel-256k-sample-60msps-logic-analyzer/">http://dangerousprototypes.com/2014/04/15/new-prototype-logic-pirate-8-channel-256k-sample-60msps-logic-analyzer/</a></p>

<p>Product page: <a href="http://dangerousprototypes.com/docs/Logic_Pirate">http://dangerousprototypes.com/docs/Logic_Pirate</a></p>

<p>Available from Seeed @ <a href="http://www.seeedstudio.com/depot/Logic-Pirate-p-1750.html">http://www.seeedstudio.com/depot/Logic-Pirate-p-1750.html</a></p>

<p>Client Software: <a href="http://www.lxtreme.nl/ols/">Logic Sniffer (An alternative OLS client)</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM 3.4.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/llvm-3-dot-4-1"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T06:05:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/llvm-3-dot-4-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://heartbleed.com"><img class="left" src="/images/llvm_logo_small.png" title="&ldquo;LLVM&rdquo;" ></a>Point releases are coming to the <a href="http://www.llvm.org">LLVM</a> compiler infrastructure with the LLVM 3.4.1 release just a few days away.</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>The official LLVM 3.4.1 release is planned for 4-18 assuming that all of the testing goes well. Details for testing can be found via the<a href="http://lists.cs.uiuc.edu/pipermail/llvmdev/2014-April/072066.html"> LLVM mailing list</a>.</p>

<p>I am staying on the bleeding-edge for my bare metal ARM work, so I will continue to stay on the master branch (3.5.0):</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>./clang &mdash;version
</span><span class='line'>clang version 3.5.0
</span><span class='line'>Target: arm-none&mdash;eabi
</span><span class='line'>Thread model: posix</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARM: LLVM and Why No GPL]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/arm-llvm-and-why-no-gpl"/>
    <updated>2014-04-11T07:28:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/arm-llvm-and-why-no-gpl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a follow up to my last post about ARM&rsquo;s annoucement concerning their move to clang/LLVM.</p>

<p>Seems that more of the GPL-only mindset are upset that ARM is another company that is picking up and carrying the LLVM torch for their future development activities.</p>

<p>My take on it is it is a good thing, something they could not do with GCC without violating the GPL license that they would have to follow.  Clang/LLVM is licensed with a BSD-style license and not wanting to get in to a religious war over open source licensing, their LLVM selection and thus license choice allows them to keep things proprietary while working on new designs and code and releasing that to development partners like they currently do with their in-house ARM/Keli development environment. Then there is the problem of linking and including non-open code in end-user projects if they would have chosen GCC, this is a non-trivial problem for private and public companies dealing with IP that has extreme competition.</p>

<p>As ARM&rsquo;s new designs become public, they can then push LLVM changes to the public branch and, we as end-users, then get to enjoy the benefits of what they can release. Will there be code components that they alway keep private and/or charge for in their commerical &lsquo;ulitmate&rsquo; compiler version, maybe, but the code that does make it to the git repo will be vetted by the company that actually produces the MCU designs. Good enough for me, GPL be damned in this case&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARM Starts Move to LLVM]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/arm-starts-move-to-llvm"/>
    <updated>2014-04-10T22:03:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/arm-starts-move-to-llvm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Very cool news from ARM Holding the other day. They are formally adopting clang/LLVM as their future compiler. If you have been following LLVM commits, you might have noticed that AArch64 support has been making progress for quite some time, and now ARM is publicly releasing v6 of their compiler:</p>

<blockquote><p>ARM announces the availability of version 6 of the ARM Compiler, the reference code generation toolchain for the ARM® architecture. ARM Compiler 6 adopts the Clang and LLVM open source compiler framework, channeling contributions from the whole ARM Partnership to improve code quality, performance and power efficiency of software on ARM processors.</p>

<p>The flexible and modern Clang and LLVM infrastructure provides a solid foundation for ARM&rsquo;s code generation tools. Clang is a C/C++ compiler front end based on a modular architecture with well-defined interfaces for applying complimentary tools such as code analyzers and code generators. Clang also offers improved diagnostic capabilities, leading to higher quality code and shorter development cycles.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.arm.com/about/newsroom/arm-compiler-builds-on-open-source-llvm-technology.php">ARM&rsquo;s Press Release</a></p>

<p>I am really looking forward to when they start contributing on the existing Cortex-M backend in LLVM. :&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
