<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: microsoft | SushiHangover]]></title>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/blog/categories/microsoft/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-14T03:13:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[RobertN]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OS-X + Mono + Rosyln + CodeFormatter]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/mono-plus-rosyln-plus-codeformatter/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-25T06:20:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/mono-plus-rosyln-plus-codeformatter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>CodeFormatter is a tool that uses Roslyn to automatically rewrite the source to follow Microsoft&rsquo;s coding styles, which are <a href="https://github.com/dotnet/corefx/blob/master/Documentation/coding-style.md">documented here</a>.</p>

<p>CodeFormatter has been released as open-source for 6 months now, but I have not had a chance to look at it.</p>

<p>With Roslyn compiling on OS-X and I had a couple of projects that really needed to be cleaned up, I thought I would give it a try.</p>

<p>15 minutes in total to clone the repo and get things built properly, would have been quicker but the VS solution file is not very Xamanin Studio/MonoDevelop friendly as it includes ToolVersion 14 items (That would be included in VS 2015 beta).</p>

<p>But those projects are not needed to get the main program working&hellip;</p>

<h3>mono ./CodeFormatter.exe</h3>

<pre><code>Must specify at least one project / solution / rsp to format
CodeFormatter [/file:&lt;filename&gt;] [/lang:&lt;language&gt;] [/c:&lt;config&gt;[,&lt;config&gt;...]&gt;]
    [/copyright:&lt;file&gt; | /nocopyright] [/tables] [/nounicode]
    [/rule(+|-):rule1,rule2,...]  [/verbose]
    &lt;project, solution or response file&gt;

    /file        - Only apply changes to files with specified name
    /lang        - Specifies the language to use when a responsefile is
                   specified. i.e. 'C#', 'Visual Basic', ... (default: 'C#')
    /c           - Additional preprocessor configurations the formatter
                   should run under.
    /copyright   - Specifies file containing copyright header.
                   Use ConvertTests to convert MSTest tests to xUnit.
    /nocopyright - Do not update the copyright message.
    /tables      - Let tables opt out of formatting by defining
                   DOTNET_FORMATTER
    /nounicode   - Do not convert unicode strings to escape sequences
    /rule(+|-)   - Enable (default) or disable the specified rule
    /rules       - List the available rules
    /verbose     - Verbose output
</code></pre>

<h3>mono ./CodeFormatter.exe /rules</h3>

<pre><code>Name                 Description
==============================================
BraceNewLine         :Ensure all braces occur on a new line
Copyright            :Insert the copyright header into every file
NewLineAbove         :Ensure there is a new line above the first namespace and using in the file
CustomCopyright      :Remove any custom copyright header from the file
UsingLocation        :Place using directives outside namespace declarations
UnicodeLiterals      :Use unicode escape sequence instead of unicode literals
ExplicitVisibility   :Ensure all members have an explicit visibility modifier
IllegalHeaders       :Remove illegal headers from files
FormatDocument       :Run the language specific formatter on every document
ExplicitThis         :Remove explicit this/Me prefixes on expressions except where necessary
ReadonlyFields       :Mark fields which can be readonly as readonly
FieldNames           :Prefix private fields with _ and statics with s_
</code></pre>

<p> I&rsquo;ll be checking next to see if it really works on some source code. ;-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
