<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: pull request | SushiHangover]]></title>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/blog/categories/pull-request/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-13T15:49:44-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[RobertN]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git : Your Github based fork's pull request is rejected, kind-of, now what?]]></title>
    <link href="http://sushihangover.github.io/git-your-githubs-fork-pull-request-is-rejected-kind-of-now-what/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-24T07:46:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://sushihangover.github.io/git-your-githubs-fork-pull-request-is-rejected-kind-of-now-what</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left <a" src="href="http://sushihangover.github.io/images/gitlogo.png">http://sushihangover.github.io/images/gitlogo.png</a>"> So you have a Github fork of a project and you find a problem. You whip up a fix, commit it in a local branch and push it to your fork you Github. Than you issue a pull request to the upstream repo. Life is good. <img class="right <a" src="href="http://sushihangover.github.io/images/github_logo.png">http://sushihangover.github.io/images/github_logo.png</a>"></p>

<p>But&hellip; your pull request is &lsquo;rejected&rsquo;, kind-of, as the fix is applied differently to their branch. Now your GitHub and local repo are history mismatched to the upstream master. Fetching upstream and merging upstream/master produces conflicts ;-(</p>

<p>First, I do not want to lose the commit that I did do. I want to keep the work/history so a &lsquo;simple&rsquo; git hard reset to a prior sha is out of the question.</p>

<p>So lets put your changes on a new branch and reset the master branch back to match the upstream.</p>

<h3>Move last commit to a new branch</h3>

<p>Note: You <em>will</em> lose uncommitted work, stash first if needed!</p>

<pre><code>git branch newbranch
git reset --hard HEAD~1 # Go back 1 commit or use SHA
git checkout newbranch
</code></pre>

<h3>Re-sync your Github fork</h3>

<p>Now, lets get everything re-sync&rsquo;d.</p>

<pre><code>git checkout master
</code></pre>

<p>Since you already push this branch to your Github fork, you will see the message:</p>

<pre><code>"Your branch is behind 'origin/master' by 1 commit, and can be fast-forwarded."
</code></pre>

<p>That contains <em>your</em> fix, but you need to merge in the upstream/master changes.</p>

<pre><code>git fetch upstream
git merge upstream/master
</code></pre>

<p>And your local master should <em>Fast-forward</em> to match the upstream. All is good, except your repo on Github is not correct as it contains your original commit on the wrong branch.</p>

<pre><code>git push --force
</code></pre>

<p>If you want to keep (backup) that new branch to Github than use the following instead:</p>

<pre><code>git push --all --force
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> You should not be forcing a push if others have already pulled from your repo/fork. That causes bad git mojo and everyone else that pulled your repo will need to be notified that you &lsquo;changed&rsquo; history&hellip; That is a git fixup story for another day.</p>

<h3>Moral of the story:</h3>

<p>Create a bugfix branch with your fixes. It should have one commit (rebase if needed) that will fast-forward and issue your pull-request from that branch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
